Inventory of the American Institutes for Research reports
Hoover Institution Archives
American Institutes for Research reports
1960-1987
91023
Hoover Institution Archives
50 manuscript boxes (20.8 linear feet)
Relates to development and evaluation of educational programs and methodologies, career guidance and training programs, and study of human behavior in various specific aspects.
American Institutes for Research.
Access
Collection is stored off-site. It may be possible to have a limited number of boxes brought to the archives reading room for examination. A minimum of two days notice is required. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
American non-profit institution for educational and social science research.
Scope and Content of Collection
Relates to development and evaluation of educational programs and methodologies, career guidance and training programs, and study of human behavior in various specific aspects.
Education--United States.; Educational evaluation.; Vocational guidance.; Occupational training.; Behavioral assessment.
- General Topics File
  General note
  There are no Project PLAN (670) reports in storage.
  - F16. Higher education in the Dominican Republic, 1966 November (Box 1)
  - F23. Experimental investigation of attitude change procedures suggested by contrast and assimilation phenomenon, 1967 May
  - F27. Experimental design for comparing the effects of instructional media programming procedures, 1968 May
  - F29. Employee mental health and industrial nursing practices
    - Progress report #2, 1968 June
    - Progress report #3, 1969 July
  - F31. Effects of cylert (magnesium-pemoline) on physiological, physical proficiency, and psychomotor performance measures, 1967 August
  - F36. Parent education in positive mental health, 1968 May
  - F37. Community development training in Honduras, 1966 October
  - F43. Evaluation of Pittsburgh preservice training program for the National Teacher Corps, 1966 October
  - F44. Social requirements of successful work
    - Report, 1969 April
    - Progress report #2
    - Final report
  - F45. Development of a program to teach standard American English to speakers of non-standard dialects, Phase I: Investigation of speech problems among Job Corpsmen, 1967 January (Box 2)
  - F46. Exploration of oral/informal technical communication behavior, 1967 March
  - F49. Study in improving performance of complex tasks
    - Report, 1970 January
    - Report #4
    - Report #8, 2 copies
    - Final report, 3 copies
  - F57. Science information requirements of scientists: Feasibility study for determining requirements of biological information services and systems
    - Report, 1967 November
    - Technical reports #1, 2, 3, 4
    - Final report, 2 copies
  - F59. Motivational effects of knowledge of results, 1969 April
  - F61. Vocational education in Siskiyou County, 1967 April (Box 3)
  - F63. Plan of action to be followed by contractors in developing each of four proposed multimedia courses of instruction U.S. Naval Academy, 1967 March
  - 664. Troop-community relations in Thailand
    - Progress report, 1969 April
    - Progress report, 1969 July
  - 668. Review of examination program of New York State Department of Civil Service, 1967 July
  - F71. Evaluation plan for Greene Joint Vocational School, 1967 September
  - F72. Identifying and formulating educational problems, 1967 December
  - F75. Telephone products and services for Bell System salesmen, 1969 April
  - F76. School community communication model: Specific behavioral concerns of the community for its youth, 1968 July
  - F78. Methods of presentation of national assessment to 9-year-olds, 1968
  - F82. A systems analysis of the Subscriber Service Department, 1968 May (Box 4)
    - Details of Medicare
    - Reading the Medicare HIC
    - Writing the letter
  - F83. Development of a comprehensive training program for managerial and professional personnel
    - Second year progress report, 1968 October
    - Seminar prog. professional and supervisory health care personnel
    - Final report, 1968 April
  - F85. Study of training equipment and individual differences: The effects of subject matter variables
    - Report, 1968 May
    - Supplemental report, 1968 August
  - F87. Special education instruction materials center network: Pilot evaluation of two prototype centers, 1968 August
  - F91. Analysis and evaluation of present and future multi-media needs in higher education, 1968 June
  - F94. Trial and testing of experimental guidance curriculum, 1967 December; 2 copies
  - F96. Evaluation of listening comprehension test of disadvantaged junior high school boys, 1968 June; 2 copies
  - G3. Sequencing of instruction in relation to hierarchies of competence. Monograph No. 3, 1967 October (Box 5)
  - 805. Foundations for success in educating disadvantaged children, 1968 December
  - G12. Preliminary definition of scope of future ERIC clearinghouses
    - Report, 1968 April
    - Analysis of content, dissemination, and use of ERIC materials, 1968 August
    - Research and analysis to define requirements for 1968-71 ERIC system. Vols. I, II, III, 1969 January
  - G18. Experimental evaluation of ELS teacher education program
    - Report of the first formal tryout, 1969 April
    - Skills inventory, 1970 February; 2 copies
    - Final report, 1970 February
  - G21. Study and evaluation: Self-concept improvement, teachers and students under Title III
    - Interim report, 1967 November
    - Final report, 1968 June; 2 copies
  - G26. Development of taxonomy of human performance (Box 6)
    - Technical report #1, 1968 December
    - Technical report #2, 1969 February; 2 copies
    - Technical report #3, 1969 December; 2 copies
    - Technical report #4, 1969 March
    - Technical progress report #1, 1968 November
    - Technical progress report #2, 1969 February
    - Technical progress report #3, 1970 October; 2 copies
  - G29. Review and redesign of Marine Corps engineer mechanics course, 1968
  - G30. Self enhancing education, 1968 September
  - 737. Analysis of U.S. Army accident data, 1969 August
  - 739. Sports as a social institution: A sociological analysis of some functions of sports in American society, 1969 October (Box 7)
  - 750. Impact of economic, social, and political action programs
    - Semi-annual progress report for March 1969 - August 1969
    - Semi-annual progress report for September 1969 - February 1970
    - Second follow-up of village police program, 1970 November
  - G52. Study of selected exemplary programs for education of disadvantaged children
    - Part I, 1968 September; 4 copies
    - Part II, 1968 September
      Scope and Contents note
      Both parts dated September 1968.
  - G53. Ethnic group membership as moderator of job performance (Box 8)
    - Technical report #1, 1970 April
    - Technical report #2, 1970 September
  - G58. Development and evaluation of comprehensive career guidance system
    - Technical reports #1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8
    - Final report, 1970
  - 761. Stimulating educational information-seeking and changes in student attitude toward vocational education by videotape and film presentations
    - Final report, 1970 August
  - 762. Training program for Peru agricultural extension/rural development (Box 9)
    - Final report, 1969 January; 2 copies
  - 764. 3-factor diagnostic test of word recognition for beginning adult readers
    - Visual-audio test of word recognition for beginning adult readers, 1969 December
  - 765. Report of evaluation of CAP project: Conceptual and perceptual development through curricular design
    - Report, 1970 June
    - Evaluation activities related to conceptual... Florida public schools (multiple copies)
  - 767. Job corps language program, 1969
  - 771. Maintenance technician's performance curves
    - Interim report, 1969
    - Monthly contract status reports #9-#17
  - 772. Development of military planning process, 1969 June
  - 774. Development of procedures for programming televised or filmed instructional units
    - Final report, 1969 September
  - 775. Assessing financial needs of higher education and fiscal capacity resources
    - Final report, 1969 October
  - 776. Study of training equipment and individual differences
    - Progress reports #1-#15
    - Study plan report
    - Technical report: Research on interactive relationships among learner characteristics, types of learning, instructional methods, and subject matter variables, 1970 March
    - Technical report: Research on interactive relationships among learner characteristics, types of learning, instructional methods, and subject matter variables (supplemental report), 1970 March
    - Final report, 1970
  - 778. Requirements for simulating occupancy conditions of large protective shelters (Box 10)
    - Report, 1970 August
    - Feasibility of use of non-OCD sponsored large shelter occupancy tests for research, 1969 August
    - Shelter habitability studies to determine effectiveness of a televised information program, 1969 August
    - Model large individual shelter plans, final report, 1971 July
    - Requirements for simulating occupancy conditions of large protective shelters
    - Quarterly progress reports: 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 5th, 6th
    - Exploratory study to determine effects of physical hazard... Final report
    - Phase 2, final report, 1971 June
  - 779. Feasibility of installing and managing an underwater interpretive facility at Acadia National Park
    - Final report, 1970 February
  - 797. Peace Corps training program for Paraguay: Agriculture and education, 1969 April
  - 801. Evaluation of Title III programs in Detroit public schools (Box 11)
    - Report - 1st year's activities, 1969 December
    - Interim report - 2nd year's activities, part I
    - Interim report - 2nd year's activities, part II (technical supplement)
    - Report - 2nd year's activities, technical supplement, 1970 August
    - Report - 3rd year's activities, part I, 1970 September
    - Report - 3rd year's activities, part II (technical supplement), 1970 September
  - 804. Human resources development in Korea
    - Final report, 1969 October
  - 805. Foundations for success in educating disadvantaged children
    - Final report, 1968 December
  - 810. Project ABLE (Box 12)
    - 15th technical report, 1970 April
    - Selected documents from 15th technical report
    - Development and evaluation of experimental curriculum for New Quincy Vocational-Technical School, 1970 September
    - Mathematics curriculum, 1970
  - 815. Development of pilot performance references scales
    - Progress reports (bound together), 1970
  - 816. Final report to Centro de estudos de testes e pesquisas psicológicas during 1969
  - 820. Effective use of mental health research information
    - Final report, 1971 January
    - Final report appendices
  - 822. Evaluation of Ellson's programmed tutoring technique for reading instruction (Box 13)
    - Final report, 1969 March
  - 827. Evaluation of So. Oyster Bay Supplementary Education Center
    - Final report, 1969 June
  - 830. Study of further selected exemplary programs for education of disadvantaged children, 3 copies
  - 833. Effects of contingency management and quasi-individual instruction on academic performance and attitude
    - Progress reports
    - Final report, 1970 November
  - 836. Longitudinal study of demonstration education programs, 1970 July (Box 14)
    - Progress reports (bound together)
  - 842. West African Examination Council
    - Semi-annual reports, 1970 January-June, July-December; 1971 January-June
    - Test development and research, final report, 1973 November
  - 843. Project PACE (Police and Community Enterprise): Program for change in police-community behaviors
    - Final report, 1971
  - 844. Evaluating the potential of films for improving self-image in minority group children
    - Interim technical report, 1969 December
    - Progress reports (bound together)
  - 845. Development of an information system for the medical uses of computers - MEDUCOMP
    - Final report, 1970 December
  - 847. An investigation of attitude change
    - Final report, 1972 November
  - 848. A study of selected programs for vocational education in secondary schools (Box 15)
    - Final report, 1970 January
  - 852. A survey of computing activities in secondary schools
    - Final report, 1970 October
  - 853. Trainee and instructor task quantification: Development of quantitative indices and a predictive methodology
    - Final report, 1971 January
  - 863. Exploratory assessment of CAP evaluation activities: Vol. 2, catalog of abstracts of evaluation studies
    - Final report, 1969 November
  - 864. The development of standards for driver training simulators, ranges, and modified cars
    - Progress reports (bound together), 1970
  - 867. The effects of caffeine on long-term visual monitoring
    - Final report, 1970 April; 4 copies
  - 868. Analysis of factors underlying work stoppages at Alcoa/Warrick operations
    - Final report, 1970 February
  - 879. Training project for Bonne Bell sales personnel (Box 16)
    - Development of training materials for Bonne Bell sales personnel
    - Interim report #1, 1970 March
    - Interim report #2, 1970 September
  - 881. Predicting human performance: Estimating probability of visual detection
    - Technical report #1, 1970 November
  - 882. Pornography and the sex offender: Patterns of exposure and immediate arousal effects of pornographic stimuli
    - Final report, 1970 May
  - 886. Swaziland curriculum and educational materials development, first semi-annual report
    - Semi-annual reports, 1969 December 4 - 1970 June 30, 1970 July 1 - December 31, 1973 July 1 - December 31
  - 889. Community relations research in Korea: Eight-day cold war instructor's clinic follow-up study, 1971
    - Community relations research in Korea: One-day instructor's clinic follow-up study, 1971
  - 890. Preliminary report on the evaluation of attitude change resulting from participation in project TARGET, (2 copies)
    - Troop-community relations in Thailand, quarterly progress report, 1970
  - 892. Personnel subsystem phase 1 test program for the Trunks Integrated Records Keeping System (TIRKS)
    - Vols. I, II, III, and Vol. III Appendices, 1971
    - Personnel subsystem testing for TIRKS, progress reports (bound together)
  - 893. Cooperative transnational research program in family planning behavior in Central and Eastern Europe (Box 17)
    - Children born to women denied abortion, progress report #1
    - Interim report, 1971 February
    - Final report, 1971 June
  - 894. Guidelines for the evaluation of developmental programs
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1971 March
  - 896. Development of a standardized battery of performance tests for the assessment of noise stress effects
    - Final report, 1971 April
  - 10510. Development of poisoning information training materials for professional and paraprofessional personnel
  - 10523. Factor analysis of the ability to comprehend time-compressed speech
    - Final report, 1970 August
  - 20000. Marine Corps human relations training
    - Status report, 1971 December
    - The Marine Corps human relations program: A study in the institutionalization of social change
    - Final technical report, 1975 July
  - 20300. Current approaches to comprehensive planning for youth development and delinquency prevention
    - Final report, 1971 January
  - 20500. Psychosocial components of repeated abortion-seeking behavior in Hungary
    - Final report, 1971 July
  - 20131. Effects of ancillary information upon photo-interpreter performance
    - Final report
  - 20600. A method for constructing career paths to meet requirements of tomorrow's police force (Box 18)
    - Guidelines for examining and constructing police career path programs
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Technical report, 1971 March
    - Final report (multiple copies), 1971 July; 2 copies
  - 20800. National program to encourage the use of restraint systems
    - Summary report on program feasibility for service clubs, 1971 February
    - Feasibility survey for rental companies, 1971 April
    - "Model" regulations for taxi-cabs, 1971 April
    - Summary of current safety belt programs of taxi cab companies and regulatory agencies, 1971 May
    - Progress report, 1971 May 31
    - Draft program kit for national service clubs, 1971 June
    - Program material specifications for rental car companies, 1971 June
    - Survey results of private companies, 1971 June
    - Progress report, 1971 July 1; 2 copies
    - Interim report, 1971 October 29
    - Area C: Economic and legal motivation. Task 7: Insurance, 1971 December
    - Programs concerning governmental captive target audiences, 1972 March
    - Area C: Economic and legal motivation. Task 8: Legislation-FR
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Suggestions for possible program activities to increase the use of auto
    - Summary of film evaluations
  - 20900. Computer-based instructional management system: The Conwell approach (Box 19)
    - Interim report, 1970 November
  - 21200. Report of the technical advisory services provided to the regional center for educational innovation and technology (Innotech)
    - Quarterly reports #1, 2, and 5, 1970 May, June-September; 2 copies each
    - Semi-annual report, 1970 December
    - Final report, 1971 July; 2 copies
    - Technical advisory services to Innotech (Box 20)
      - Progress reports #8, #9
      - Progress reports #10, 13
      - Final report
    - The IMPACT system for low-cost primary education
    - Use of community resources in providing low cost primary education
    - Final report, 1973 November
    - Final report, 1975 July
  - 21400. Cooperative longitudinal study of demonstration education programs
    - Interim technical report #1, 1972 May
    - Final status report: Implementation Phase, Year 2, 1972 May
    - Report to the schools, 1972 October
    - Verification of the longitudinal study questionnaire data, 1973 January (Box 21)
    - Final status report: Implementation Phase, Year 3, 1973 May
    - Interim technical report #2, 1973 June
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Impact of educational innovation on student performance: Project methods and finding for three cohorts (Project LONGSTEP)
    - Final report: Volume I, 1976 April
    - Final report: Volume I supplement, 1976 September
    - Final report: Volume II, 1976 September
    - Final report: Volume I appendices, 1976 April
    - Final report: Volume II appendix report, 1976 September
    - Final report: Volume I executive summary, 1976 April
  - 21500. Study of job performance of worker-trainees (Box 22)
    - Progress report, 1971 January
    - Final report, 1972 July
  - 21600. Planning, developing, and field testing career guidance programs
    - A manual and report, 1972 June
    - Progress reports (bound together)
  - 21700. Evaluation of selected teacher training projects supported by the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
    - Progress reports (bound together)
  - 21800. Effectiveness of educational laboratories and centers: A system for the evaluation of educational research and development products
    - Documentation report: Results of the pilot test of the NCERD/OPPE products evaluation system, 1972 June
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report, 1973 February
  - 21900. Selection and description of educational products for a study of the development and impact of such products
    - Interim report #1, 1971 April
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Product development report #1: First year communication skills program, 1971 September
    - Product development report #2: Hawaii English program, 1971 November
    - Product development report #3: Intermediate science curriculum study, 1971 November (Box 23)
    - Product development report #4: Science curriculum improvement study, 1971 November
    - Product development report #5: The Sullivan reading program, 1971 November
    - Product development report #6: The creative learning group drug education program, 1971 December
    - Product development report #7: The Frostig program for perceptual-motor development
    - Product development report #8: Science - A process approach, 1971 December
    - Product development report #9: Variable modular scheduling via computer, 1971 December
    - Product development report #10: Sesame Street, 1971 December
    - Product development report #11: Arithmetic proficiency training program, 1972 January
    - Product development report #12: Distar instructional system, 1972 January
    - Product development report #15: Materials and activities for teachers and children - The Match program, 1972 January
    - Product development report #16: Developmental Economic Education Program (DEEP), 1972 January
    - Product development report #17: Individually prescribed instruction - mathematics, 1972 January
    - Product development report #18: The Cluster Concept Program, 1972 January
    - Product development report #20: Facilitating inquiry in the classroom, 1972 March
    - Product development report #21: Program for Learning in Accordance with Needs (PLAN), 1972 January
  - 22000. Audio/video recording in pilot instructor training (Box 24)
    - Design for demonstration of an audio/video recording system in pilot instructor training
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Interim technical report, 1970 October
    - Final report, 1972 February; 3 copies
  - 22300. A comparative study of proprietary and non-proprietary vocational training programs
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Final report - Volume I, 1972 November
    - Final report - Volume II: Appendices, 1972 November; 2 copies
  - 22400. Development of course content and instructional materials/aids for the training of educational research, development, diffusion, and evaluation personnel
    - Final report, 1971 September
    - Supplementary final report, 1973 May
  - 22500. Early growth planning study for Project LSEE (Box 25)
    - Progress reports (bound together)
    - Interim report #1: A conceptual system for the classification of variables for the early growth planning study of the longitudinal study of educational effects, 1973 August
    - Interim report #2: A classification and listing of potential variables in the early growth planning study for the longitudinal study of educational effects, 1970 October
    - Interim report #3: A report on the collection of relevant information for selected potential variables in the early growth planning study, 1970 November
    - Interim report #4: Recommendations regarding the time at which an early age cohort might be started in the longitudinal study of educational effects, 1970 December